<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0xHyp3rion Blog</title>
    <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 0xHyp3rion Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:24:24 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Snake Oil: The Dark Side of MSSPs</title>
      <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/cyber-snake-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:24:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/cyber-snake-oil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: Despite the tone of this article, I&amp;rsquo;m not making the claim that all MSSPs are useless, and I do know that there are many MSSPs that believe in their overall mission and deliver quality results. This article isn&amp;rsquo;t about the good apples in the bunch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;managed-security&#34;&gt;Managed Security&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The state of our cybersecurity posture in the US is pitiful. Commentators and industry experts have for years now been pointing out the talent shortage that exists in the industry, as well as the various ailments that plague the average SOC analyst and CISO on a day-to-day basis (alert fatigue, long hours, high liability, stubborn executives allocating slim budgets to IT teams, and beyond). Outside of the issues for industry professionals, individual organizations also have a problem: Cybersecurity can be expensive. Forming an in-house team requires talent, training, and technology, all of which come at a hefty price tag that can easily exceed the total net revenues of a small to mid-sized business. To counter this problem, MSSPs, or Managed Security Service Providers (Security as a Service) started becoming a business model. These companies promise that they&amp;rsquo;ll solve all of your cybersecurity needs, have impressive marketing, and affordable rates (typically with a contract that locks you in for a set amount of time) that allow you to focus more on your bottom line while they shoulder the burden of focusing on the security threats that might impact your organization. The charming words are all the same: They&amp;rsquo;ll focus on your organization&amp;rsquo;s needs and tailor all of it to what you need to give you the most peace of mind. They have a dedicated SOC team, online 24/7, monitoring your environment and ready to react when the unpredictable happens. Think of it like your average home security system like ADT, except for computers safeguarding the data of your company and your customers. After Russia invaded Ukraine in 2022, the need for domestic cybersecurity solutions exploded in popularity due to rising fears of a cyber war with Russia, and business has been booming ever since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the Complex World of Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/navigating-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:11:12 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/navigating-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-primer-for-beginners-and-encouragement-for-junior-to-mid-level-soc&#34;&gt;A Primer for Beginners and Encouragement for Junior to Mid-Level SOC&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world of Cybersecurity is, in a nutshell, complex. There is no one size fits all solution to prevent against threats, and there is no one size fits all book, instructional video, or article that will help anyone wanting to succeed in the field. The technology field is dynamic, constantly changing, and within every broad category of tech exists broad specializations that each have their own specializations within the specialization. As technology grows, changes, and adapts, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be able to keep up to date with these changes and to understand the overall broad concepts where all of these puzzle pieces fit into. Cybersecurity is a specific specialization within the field of Information Technology that focuses on securing (and/or breaking) pieces of technology to make those systems more secure. Where do we start? How do we navigate the industry? And most importantly, how do we keep from falling behind?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSINT Challenge</title>
      <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/osint-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:50:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/osint-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A little backstory to this post: I was socializing with some of my Cybersecurity friends in an online community when one of them (who was travelling for work at the time) posted the below image, and said &amp;ldquo;OSINT challenge! Where am I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;osint_challenge_full.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I get excited when these types of &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo; are presented. They pique my curiosity, and it&amp;rsquo;s also a great little exercise in critical thinking. This writeup will elaborate on my thought process from start to finish and methodology to arrive at a conclusion, but a big disclaimer here is that it&amp;rsquo;s never a one-size-fits-all solution, and anyone&amp;rsquo;s results and process will differ. My ultimate hope is that if you&amp;rsquo;re new to OSINT, or looking to get other insights, that this will help to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
