<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on 0xHyp3rion Blog</title>
        <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on 0xHyp3rion Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:50:22 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>OSINT Challenge</title>
            <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/osint-challenge/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:50:22 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/osint-challenge/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little backstory to this post: I was socializing with some of my Cybersecurity friends in an online community when one of them (who was travelling for work at the time) posted the below image, and said &amp;ldquo;OSINT challenge! Where am I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;osint_challenge_full.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get excited when these types of &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo; are presented. They pique my curiosity, and it&amp;rsquo;s also a great little exercise in critical thinking. This writeup will elaborate on my thought process from start to finish and methodology to arrive at a conclusion, but a big disclaimer here is that it&amp;rsquo;s never a one-size-fits-all solution, and anyone&amp;rsquo;s results and process will differ. My ultimate hope is that if you&amp;rsquo;re new to OSINT, or looking to get other insights, that this will help to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>A little backstory to this post: I was socializing with some of my Cybersecurity friends in an online community when one of them (who was travelling for work at the time) posted the below image, and said &ldquo;OSINT challenge! Where am I?&rdquo;</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_full.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_full.jpg"></p>
<p>I get excited when these types of &ldquo;challenges&rdquo; are presented. They pique my curiosity, and it&rsquo;s also a great little exercise in critical thinking. This writeup will elaborate on my thought process from start to finish and methodology to arrive at a conclusion, but a big disclaimer here is that it&rsquo;s never a one-size-fits-all solution, and anyone&rsquo;s results and process will differ. My ultimate hope is that if you&rsquo;re new to OSINT, or looking to get other insights, that this will help to some degree.</p>
<h2 id="step-1-start-with-the-obvious">Step 1: Start With the Obvious</h2>
<p>When investigating anything I always start by formulating questions. Things like &ldquo;Who, what how when, where, why?&rdquo; don&rsquo;t necessarily fit into a picture, but a good mindset when you&rsquo;re utterly clueless is to start broadly and then narrow it down into more granular chunks.</p>
<p>Looking at the above image, the first question I ask myself is:</p>
<p><em>What&rsquo;s most prominent in the setting?</em></p>
<p>There&rsquo;s a big clear &ldquo;Buc-ee&rsquo;s&rdquo; storefront being reflected in the passenger window of the car. The sky is big, blue, and wide open, with no trees, hills, or mountains visible on the horizon. It looks pretty dry there.</p>
<p>These are our biggest clues as to what region this is. If you&rsquo;re not from the United States, you&rsquo;d start with a Google search, possibly researching what Buc-ee&rsquo;s is and where they&rsquo;re mostly located. I already know. It&rsquo;s a prominent gas station chain in the southern USA. I&rsquo;ve sadly never been to one, but there&rsquo;s rumors they might be expanding into my state; but until then, I at least know about it from the myths and legends of my people. Either way, Google is your friend.</p>
<p>A quick visit to Google Maps yields most of the Buc-ee&rsquo;s locations in the US:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_1.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_1.png"></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a little surprised because I thought there were more of these locations in more states, but I&rsquo;m quickly filled with more hope from checking out the Wikipedia entry on Buc-ee&rsquo;s, confirming there aren&rsquo;t that many, with only ~50 locations in the US:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_2.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_2.png"></p>
<p>This is actually promising, because it allows me to start narrowing down the more likely possibilities.</p>
<h2 id="step-2-process-of-elimination">Step 2: Process of Elimination</h2>
<p>My next focus is going to be on the landscape, and Google Street View is going to be your friend here. A quick look at the street view for the locations not in Texas (Colorado, Missouri, and Kentucky) quickly show us that these aren&rsquo;t the spot, because features exist that aren&rsquo;t in the photo: Trees, mountains/hills in the distance, so this is definitely in Texas.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d repeat the process for the Texas locations, but I&rsquo;ll save you some reading time. It&rsquo;s definitely not Houston, and another hint was that the originator of this challenge was travelling for work; so the likelihood of him being out in the middle of nowheresville, TX is pretty slim. Not completely off the table, but I&rsquo;m going to eliminate those locations as possibilities unless I&rsquo;m proven wrong.</p>
<p>Honestly, you could trial and error your way through to finding this location just by using Google Street View 50 different times, but that&rsquo;s just no fun. So let&rsquo;s try narrowing it down even further.</p>
<h2 id="step-3-get-granular">Step 3: Get Granular</h2>
<p>Looking around at the picture zoomed in, I want to find some other distinguishing characteristics. A landmark, a brand, something that stands out. I see the orange/white striped roof which I recognize as a sacred shrine to the Gods of beef, aka Whataburger, and next to it, a restaurant name I&rsquo;m not familiar with: Taco Cabana (at least I think it says Cabana, it&rsquo;s a bit blurry):</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_3.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_3.png"></p>
<p>There&rsquo;s also what appears to be a car wash:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_4.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_4.png"></p>
<p>And what I&rsquo;m assuming to be across the street in the background is a strip mall, with a Hobby Lobby and Ross in there.</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_5.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_5.png"></p>
<p>Again, this further confirms that this individual is somewhere in Texas. The American South is the only region in the world where you can get grandma&rsquo;s yarn for her knitting projects, a discounted jacket, a gallon bucket of pecans, gas, and get your truck washed, all within a 100 yard radius. There&rsquo;s also a sign that says &ldquo;Texas&rdquo; on the object saying &ldquo;Rent Me&rdquo; in one of the above images. So definitely Texas.</p>
<p>Out of all of these establishments, Taco Cabana seems the least well-known. At least to me. Using Google Maps again, it narrows down the possibility to 3 cities: Dallas, Austin, and San Antonio.</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_6.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_6.png"></p>
<p>So now I can confidently say that I&rsquo;m looking for an aerial view of a Taco Cabana next door to a Whataburger, by a car wash, across the street from a Buc-ee&rsquo;s, with a strip mall across from all of it. This makes the search much, much, easier. So I decide to start with the Dallas area, and eyeball the image again to get a rough idea of how these establishments are all laid out. I redo my search for Buc-ee&rsquo;s since there aren&rsquo;t as many clustered together, and within 2 looks I finally find a hit:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_7.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_7.png"></p>
<p>Google Street View of the Buc-ee&rsquo;s has almost a complete match on the location, in nearly the same spot as the original photo was taken. Jackpot!</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_8.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_8.png"></p>
<p>So our friend was at the Buc-ee&rsquo;s on 506 I-20, Terrell, TX 75160</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>This was honestly a pretty easy OSINT exercise because of all of the prominent brand names, and having a general understanding of where the brands are concentrated and what various geographical and topological features might hint towards in terms of regions and locales is a huge one-up.</p>
<p>Performing OSINT is a lot like learning how to hack. You can do it out the gate, but it becomes far easier having pre-existing knowledge and understanding of contextual information, which comes from being curious about anything and everything you look at.</p>
<p>My parents used to tell me that my endless hours of going down Wikipedia rabbit holes and perusing Google Earth was a waste of time. Well, now I can confidently say that it wasn&rsquo;t; it was just setting the foundation for a skillset that I didn&rsquo;t know I&rsquo;d be using until later on in life.</p>
<p>The most important thing to remember is that asking yourself questions are your friend. Start big, work your way down, and keep refining your process until you find a methodology that works for you.</p>
<p>Happy hunting!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
