<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on 0xHyp3rion Blog</title>
        <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on 0xHyp3rion Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:24:24 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Cyber Snake Oil: The Dark Side of MSSPs</title>
            <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/cyber-snake-oil/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:24:24 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/cyber-snake-oil/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: Despite the tone of this article, I&amp;rsquo;m not making the claim that all MSSPs are useless, and I do know that there are many MSSPs that believe in their overall mission and deliver quality results. This article isn&amp;rsquo;t about the good apples in the bunch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;managed-security&#34;&gt;Managed Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state of our cybersecurity posture in the US is pitiful. Commentators and industry experts have for years now been pointing out the talent shortage that exists in the industry, as well as the various ailments that plague the average SOC analyst and CISO on a day-to-day basis (alert fatigue, long hours, high liability, stubborn executives allocating slim budgets to IT teams, and beyond). Outside of the issues for industry professionals, individual organizations also have a problem: Cybersecurity can be expensive. Forming an in-house team requires talent, training, and technology, all of which come at a hefty price tag that can easily exceed the total net revenues of a small to mid-sized business. To counter this problem, MSSPs, or Managed Security Service Providers (Security as a Service) started becoming a business model. These companies promise that they&amp;rsquo;ll solve all of your cybersecurity needs, have impressive marketing, and affordable rates (typically with a contract that locks you in for a set amount of time) that allow you to focus more on your bottom line while they shoulder the burden of focusing on the security threats that might impact your organization. The charming words are all the same: They&amp;rsquo;ll focus on your organization&amp;rsquo;s needs and tailor all of it to what you need to give you the most peace of mind. They have a dedicated SOC team, online 24/7, monitoring your environment and ready to react when the unpredictable happens. Think of it like your average home security system like ADT, except for computers safeguarding the data of your company and your customers. After Russia invaded Ukraine in 2022, the need for domestic cybersecurity solutions exploded in popularity due to rising fears of a cyber war with Russia, and business has been booming ever since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Disclaimer: Despite the tone of this article, I&rsquo;m not making the claim that all MSSPs are useless, and I do know that there are many MSSPs that believe in their overall mission and deliver quality results. This article isn&rsquo;t about the good apples in the bunch.</em></p>
<h2 id="managed-security">Managed Security</h2>
<p>The state of our cybersecurity posture in the US is pitiful. Commentators and industry experts have for years now been pointing out the talent shortage that exists in the industry, as well as the various ailments that plague the average SOC analyst and CISO on a day-to-day basis (alert fatigue, long hours, high liability, stubborn executives allocating slim budgets to IT teams, and beyond). Outside of the issues for industry professionals, individual organizations also have a problem: Cybersecurity can be expensive. Forming an in-house team requires talent, training, and technology, all of which come at a hefty price tag that can easily exceed the total net revenues of a small to mid-sized business. To counter this problem, MSSPs, or Managed Security Service Providers (Security as a Service) started becoming a business model. These companies promise that they&rsquo;ll solve all of your cybersecurity needs, have impressive marketing, and affordable rates (typically with a contract that locks you in for a set amount of time) that allow you to focus more on your bottom line while they shoulder the burden of focusing on the security threats that might impact your organization. The charming words are all the same: They&rsquo;ll focus on your organization&rsquo;s needs and tailor all of it to what you need to give you the most peace of mind. They have a dedicated SOC team, online 24/7, monitoring your environment and ready to react when the unpredictable happens. Think of it like your average home security system like ADT, except for computers safeguarding the data of your company and your customers. After Russia invaded Ukraine in 2022, the need for domestic cybersecurity solutions exploded in popularity due to rising fears of a cyber war with Russia, and business has been booming ever since.</p>
<h2 id="predatory-business-model">Predatory Business Model</h2>
<p>It won&rsquo;t shock anyone to point out that in a highly lucrative industry such as the Security as a Service market that these companies are only in it for the money. I&rsquo;ll even be so bold as to state that none of these companies care about the safety of your data; but you can be guaranteed that they will care and do everything under the sun to avoid liability if their negligence results in a breach for your company. An army of lawyers and piles of liability insurance policies sit at the ready, as well as carefully worded contracts that cover (almost) every possible scenario that can possibly warrant these safeguards being utilized. The likelihood of them being sued for negligence is fairly slim, however, because the reality is that since MSSPs focus on attracting small to midsized businesses that can&rsquo;t afford a proper cybersecurity program, their target customers are less likely to employ those with the level of expertise needed to properly understand and navigate through cybersecurity threats. It&rsquo;s like any other predatory business model that seeks to profit off of the naitivity of their customer base. The biggest exceptions to this rule are the IT Managers for the larger companies, who, despite being comfortable in their positions, get to pull out their hair in frustration with the shoddy security product they&rsquo;re receiving but are forced to utilize due to their almost non-existent budget which only allows them to outsource their cybersecurity solution rather than implement a rounded program. This is because the executives allocating that budget don&rsquo;t know what they&rsquo;re paying for, but the reports generated by the MSSP they&rsquo;ve hired are flooded with data showing how effective the solution is. On paper, at least.</p>
<h2 id="reports-reports-reports">Reports, Reports, Reports</h2>
<p>Reports are key. If you&rsquo;ve ever worked in an office environment, you&rsquo;ve more than likely handled at least one report, and you would know that the reports get consolidated into other reports and then compiled into another report until a final version of a report then lands its way to the desks of the executives of the company. From these reports, whatever they&rsquo;re detailing, key decisions are made, budgets are allocated, contractors are called up, and the business makes its strategic moves accordingly. MSSPs produce reports for their customers that detail the overall results of their security product, and to the non-proficient reader of said report, they can make or break whether the company continues utilizing the same vendor for their security needs. It is, therefore, imperative for the MSSP to pad these reports with as much data as possible, but can&rsquo;t lie, because that would open them up to liability. So what&rsquo;s the effective solution? Increase the volume of events that are detected by the security solution.</p>
<h2 id="the-siems">The SIEMs</h2>
<p>If you&rsquo;re already proficient in how SIEMs function, you scan skip this paragraph. If not, consider this: Your average security solution involves software (called an &ldquo;agent&rdquo;) that is installed on computers and servers. The agent collects log files from the device and directs these log files to get sent to a central server. This central server has a piece of software installed on it called a SIEM (Security Integration and Endpoint Management). The SIEM is a specialized program that parses log file data into a readable, sortable, and accessible format and can be &ldquo;tuned&rdquo; to generate alerts (similar to an IT support ticket) that highlight specific concerns detected in the logs, depending on how the SIEM is tuned. The more sensitive it is, the more alerts will generate. The less sensitive, the less alerts. For example, a SIEM can be tuned with a rule to generate an alert if an employee logs on to their computer after normal business hours, from which the analyst will then review the alert and correlating log files to determine if the activity is safe or a security breach. If the activity is considered a breach, they will raise the alert to the incident response team which will then take over handling and determine the next steps to be taken. The more sensitive a SIEM is tuned, the more likelihood of false-positive detections occurring; that is, a detection that the SIEM believes is a breach, but in actuality is safe and benign activity. This occurs very frequently with internet traffic. Think of it like living in a house with the door accessible by a busy sidewalk. Throughout the day you would expect various people to test the door handle and knock. It would be irritating to be notified or alerted every single time someone knocked. The same is applicable to internet traffic &ldquo;testing&rdquo; if doors are open on our systems. We don&rsquo;t need to know when someone tests the door, since it happens to frequently; but we would want to know if the door gets kicked in, or the lock gets picked, as well as track every action that the intruder took while they were inside the building. A SIEM is remarkably relevant to this analogy, and it&rsquo;s where the reports mentioned earlier get padded.</p>
<p>Many MSSPs try to push their own in-house security products. Many of these are reskins of established SIEMs already on the market, some of which you can find for free (think Elastic/Kibana).</p>
<h2 id="back-to-reports">Back to Reports</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s in the sensitivity of the SIEM solution that can make or break the business model based off of the appearance of it being an effective solution. By populating a report with data reflecting high volumes of benign detections, on paper and to the busy or otherwise non-technical executive reviewing the report, it will appear that the solution is preventing multitudes of potential breaches and playing a key role in the safeguarding of the company&rsquo;s systems and data. It&rsquo;s not lying, because it&rsquo;s showing security events that have actually occurred, and on a positive note, also provides more robust data for an analyst to dig through to baseline patterns of activity and make better-informed decisions; but the average SOC analyst is buried in these benign alerts and does not have the time, and in many cases the resources, to make an informed decision.</p>
<h2 id="alert-fatigue">Alert Fatigue</h2>
<p>This creates a common problem in the industry known as alert fatigue, which is a term used to describe the mental exhaustion that occurs after combing through endless alerts on a daily basis, typically from 10 to 12 hours a day. Compound this with the fact that MSSPs monitor more than a single organization, and every organization owns multiple computers that produce thousands of log files per day. I can attest from experience that I have been the only SOC analyst on duty during many shifts reviewing the alerts and having nobody to reach out to for guidance or support. This dilemma creates a security risk in itself because as the human brain becomes exhausted from being overwhelmed with information, the small details that could be a result of big issues such as a breach have a higher likelihood of being overlooked. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->. It also is a form of false advertising when the MSSP is advertising to its customers that it has a fully-staffed 24/7 SOC team, when the reality is the SOC team is understaffed, and overwhelmed.</p>
<h2 id="no-training">No Training</h2>
<p>Another problem plaguing SOC teams is that training is hard to come by. Many, if not most Cybersecurity professionals embark on this specialization within the field of Information Technology because they have a passion for the nature of the work, but it&rsquo;s difficult to get your foot in the door due to the high level of proficiency and trust that employers require due to the high level of liability and risk involved with the nature of the work. As a result, it&rsquo;s rare to see entry level jobs being posted, with most positions requiring years of experience, a degree in the field, and multiple security-related IT certifications under their belt. With this, being hired means you&rsquo;re expected to know how to do your job without being trained, which works well for a highly motivated self-starter, but not very well for people who don&rsquo;t know how to be that. MSSPs are more likely to hire individuals at entry level who do not have the experience, because for this business model, it&rsquo;s more important to review and clear alerts than it is to necessarily know what you&rsquo;re doing. What makes this work is that these individuals will be willing to expect a significantly lower pay scale than the industry median for entry level, because the employee is looking to get the experience, and the employer is capitalizing on the fact that they can underpay them because, well, it&rsquo;s not like the employee is going to get a better paying job somewhere else for now. I have seen the risk in this play out, with underqualified and less than knowledgeable SOC analysts clearing out glaring true-positive detections of breaches occurring, which resulted in the attacker getting to the stage of deploying ransomware; all because they didn&rsquo;t know how to review or make sense of the information they were looking at, because they were not adequately trained.</p>
<h2 id="security-theater">Security Theater</h2>
<p>There is a concept that is known in the broader security industry as &ldquo;security theater.&rdquo; Security guard firms thrive on this model by selling their employees dressed up in uniforms that, from first glance, give the guard an appearance of authority or even law enforcement, which acts as a proactive deterrent for any do-no-gooders causing them to feel intimidated or fearing they&rsquo;ll get caught and think twice about performing their illicit action. This results in less loss for the customer, as well as a feeling of safety for the customer and their clientele by seeing the physical presence of a security guard on their premises. During my time working in uniformed security, I realized the effectiveness of this concept by taking pride in my appearance and keeping myself in shape so that even if someone got close enough to me to realize I wasn&rsquo;t a police officer, my demeanor and confidence was still enough that they wouldn&rsquo;t want to mess with me. A disheveled coworker, on the other hand, would complain to me about all of the altercations and incidents that would happen during his shifts. I would shrug and just tell him to iron his uniform. The same concept exists in the MSSP market, but is slightly different, as a security solution is not a deterrent for a well-rounded attacker. Security functions a little differently in the IT world, where the threats are ever present, but can&rsquo;t be discerned until some form of tangible evidence exists that proves there is something amiss; but to a paying customer who does not understand the evolving digital threat landscape and the nature of cybersecurity, they will believe themselves to be protected from the clever marketing and promises made by the security vendor. Ironically, all of the ransomware incidents I&rsquo;ve had to respond to were a result of either the security product or an analyst failing to do what they were deployed to do, and the initial access was obtained by the attacker due to trivial, preventable misconfigurations that the customer failed to plug, assuming that the security product they were paying for would keep their environment safe.</p>
<h2 id="were-fed">We&rsquo;re F***ed</h2>
<p>Back to the opening line of this article, the state of our cybersecurity posture in the US is pitiful. Small to midsize companies are increasingly moving towards MSSPs to provide them the piece of mind they need to manage their cybersecurity posture, alongside likely being required to have some form of cybersecurity program implemented in their operation to be covered by their insurance company with non-stop prevalence of ransomware. While the intentions are noble, the reality is that by relying on these vendors for the illusion of a secure digital environment without actually understanding any of it is not only preying on naitivity, it&rsquo;s also creating the potential for a crisis in the making if, and likely when, a direct conflict breaks out with a foreign power. Despite what we are told by our government and the big tech companies, we are in a very vulnerable position. We have a near-complete reliance on network-attached devices to store information, communicate, and even to operate and function critical equipment and infrastructure: Hospitals, water treatment plants, electric grids, and beyond are all reliant on internet connectivity and computer hardware to function now in the 21st century, and in the words of Mikko Hyponen, &ldquo;If it&rsquo;s smart, it&rsquo;s vulnerable.&rdquo; This is especially concerning when we consider that when corporate and government purchases need to be made, the cheaper the better, and the cheaper options are usually produced in China exposing supply chain vulnerabilities with many hardware components being unsuitable for use due to being preloaded with malware and spyware. Hauwei was so prevalent with this that the US Government even had to issue an advisory in <!-- raw HTML omitted --> discouraging phone carriers from selling the devices. What this tells us is that cybersecurity is now more critical than ever because it&rsquo;s not simply about data anymore, it&rsquo;s about human lives. Take for example the Stuxnet virus from <!-- raw HTML omitted --> that attempted to sabatoge the Iranian nuclear program, and while not entirely successful, would have resulted in mass casualties if the centrifuges had failed and caused an explosion. Regardless of the moral position of the Iranian Nuclear Program, the takeaway from this is that a computer fault triggered by a virus could have caused human death. Please take a moment to let that sink in.</p>
<p>Where we&rsquo;re additionally vulnerable is in our level of talent. We are a society that is focused on consuming and obtaining wealth, and if an industry does not pay or show signs of stability it will not attract quality talent. This has already been highlighted as a fear in a recent article by whomawhatever <!-- raw HTML omitted --> pointing out that the massive layoffs affecting the tech sector in 2022 would result in less prospective students studying for and embarking for a career in the tech sector. This is particularly concerning for the cybersecurity arm of tech, which is not as interesting or attractive as developing a video game, and already faces a shortage of <!-- raw HTML omitted --> employees to get us up to speed. When we compare this to nations such as China, which has already developed and implemented artificial intelligence well beyond our own capabilities, and Russia, which <!-- raw HTML omitted --> prepares and educates its primary school students in computer science en masse, and then look at our own population, where 50% of today&rsquo;s youth <!-- raw HTML omitted --> aspire to be social media influencers and <!-- raw HTML omitted --> just expect technology to work since they were born with it, without actually knowing how it works (which, ironically, makes Gen-Z even more vulnerable for falling victim to online scams than baby boomers <!-- raw HTML omitted -->), I don&rsquo;t have high hopes for the next decade. I may be fear mongering here but I do believe that we have already lost the cyber arms race, and it&rsquo;s not a matter of if, but when, until we are in front of that loss face-to-face with power outages and contaminated water.</p>
<h2 id="so-what-can-we-do-about-it">So What Can We Do About It?</h2>
<p>Idealistically, and unrealistically, what is needed most is a culture shift in how we view technology and prepare our citizens for the future. We&rsquo;re already a generation behind, and I do not believe that we will bridge that gap until long after it has been too late, since the problem as a whole is not as simple as passing legislation and forcing new standards and mindsets to break through. Economically, we are driven by profitability and consumption, which has resulted in the most profitable sectors of tech catering to the consumer market with innovations that are intended to improve our lives in some way, for better or for worse. If we were to compare tech innovations side by side with our largest potential adversaries in the event of a major or global conflict, that being Russia, China, and Iran, we would see the aforementioned countries lacking in consumer tech innovations while having robust defensive, offensive, and surveillance-oriented technology; and ironically, the more we invest in innovations that somehow fill a need or aim to improve quality of life, we create security vulnerabilities in the process. The government has thankfully started noticing this gap and is trying (somewhat) to fill it, with the creation of the CISA under the DHS arm as well as <!-- raw HTML omitted --> as well as initiatives to encourage future innovators to aspire towards cybersecurity.</p>
<p>Realistically, we have to turn to ourselves and the organizations we&rsquo;re in charge of or employed by to make the necessary changes in mindset and culture that are needed to prepare ourselves for the future, which is already here.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Unravelling the Complex World of Cybersecurity</title>
            <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/navigating-cybersecurity/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:11:12 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/navigating-cybersecurity/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-primer-for-beginners-and-encouragement-for-junior-to-mid-level-soc&#34;&gt;A Primer for Beginners and Encouragement for Junior to Mid-Level SOC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of Cybersecurity is, in a nutshell, complex. There is no one size fits all solution to prevent against threats, and there is no one size fits all book, instructional video, or article that will help anyone wanting to succeed in the field. The technology field is dynamic, constantly changing, and within every broad category of tech exists broad specializations that each have their own specializations within the specialization. As technology grows, changes, and adapts, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be able to keep up to date with these changes and to understand the overall broad concepts where all of these puzzle pieces fit into. Cybersecurity is a specific specialization within the field of Information Technology that focuses on securing (and/or breaking) pieces of technology to make those systems more secure. Where do we start? How do we navigate the industry? And most importantly, how do we keep from falling behind?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="a-primer-for-beginners-and-encouragement-for-junior-to-mid-level-soc">A Primer for Beginners and Encouragement for Junior to Mid-Level SOC</h3>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>The world of Cybersecurity is, in a nutshell, complex. There is no one size fits all solution to prevent against threats, and there is no one size fits all book, instructional video, or article that will help anyone wanting to succeed in the field. The technology field is dynamic, constantly changing, and within every broad category of tech exists broad specializations that each have their own specializations within the specialization. As technology grows, changes, and adapts, it&rsquo;s important to be able to keep up to date with these changes and to understand the overall broad concepts where all of these puzzle pieces fit into. Cybersecurity is a specific specialization within the field of Information Technology that focuses on securing (and/or breaking) pieces of technology to make those systems more secure. Where do we start? How do we navigate the industry? And most importantly, how do we keep from falling behind?</p>
<h3 id="the-skills-you-need">The Skills You Need</h3>
<p>Over the summer of 2023 I spent some time exploring Discord servers tailored to ethical hacking. I learned some new ideas, and met some great people by exploring these social platforms, but a funny trend persisted in all of them: Teenagers coming in and asking for someone to teach them how to hack. All of the community who were present would be willing to help, and would start screening the person asking them what they know and what they&rsquo;re looking to do. Almost all of them just wanted to know how to hack, typically for revenge, and were quickly whisked out of the platform. The ones that were genuinely interested were surprised to learn that the entry point to learning how to hack wasn&rsquo;t with hacking itself, but was understanding how computers work, how networking works, and then progressing into security. It&rsquo;s important to note here that the overwhelming concensus about Cybersecurity from any writeup or video I&rsquo;ve read and watched points out that this is not an entry level profession, and whether you&rsquo;ve had years working IT Helpdesk, as a Programmer, as a Network Engineer, or any other field within Information Technology, wrapping your head around Cybersecurity from a skills perspective means having to learn skills and concepts that you may not have thought were necessary. Here is a list of 10 skills that I, personally, believe are crucial and foundational on the journey to approaching the field of Cybersecurity, in order of foundations to build off of:</p>
<ol>
<li>Critical Thinking</li>
<li>Communication</li>
<li>How computers work</li>
<li>Computer networking</li>
<li>System and network administration</li>
<li>Scripting</li>
<li>Programming</li>
<li>Security theory</li>
<li>Defensive security (Blue Team)</li>
<li>Offensive security (Red Team)</li>
</ol>
<p>Here&rsquo;s the good news: The broad picture can feasibly be learned in under a year. Here&rsquo;s the bad news: You&rsquo;ll have to find the time to study, learn, and practice, most likely on your own time unless you&rsquo;re fortunate enough to work somewhere that allows you to study while at work; and if you are fortunate enough to have that, you need to be taking advantage of every single second the company allows you to be studying on the clock. In the following sections I&rsquo;ll go through each skill, one by one, and detail what they are and why they&rsquo;re important.</p>
<p><em>A Note on College:</em> A college degree is highly beneficial, but that does NOT mean a college degree is required - it&rsquo;s only a possible avenue that you could consider for obtaining or learning that skillset. College helps to some degree (pun intended), but is not a definitive method, and relies more on how you spent your time in college and learning. College helps you learn how to think while learning useful skills in the process; but the mere posession of a degree is meaningless unless you know how to put what you learned to use.</p>
<p><em>A Note on Certifications:</em> Certifications are not a cure-all, end-all solution. It&rsquo;s the journey that you take while you&rsquo;re studying for the certification, and the effort to which you challenge yourself that you retain and apply the information. I&rsquo;ve met people who are very good at studying for tests and passing them, but have no idea how to apply the information on a professional level because they never took the time to practice. I&rsquo;ve likewise met people who are terrible at studying for tests and passing them, but are very good at applying information on a professional level. My biggest piece of advice here is that if you want to get a certification, choose a project to work on while studying for the certification so that you both have a way to apply the skills you&rsquo;re learning while studying, and by the end of it have a portfolio project to show a manager or prospective employer.</p>
<h2 id="1-critical-thinking">1. Critical Thinking</h2>
<p>Critical thinking is the most important skill that you absolutely must have a grip on if you want to approach Cybersecurity, and is also one of the most difficult skills to illustrate how to develop and continually keep fresh as you progress through your journey. The reason why this is most difficult to convey is because it requires an individual to look within and challenge themselves with different points of view, opinions, even facts, that might challenge the way they perceive the world and themselves. It&rsquo;s a skill that allows you to be crtical of your observations and yourself without being judgemental, and to be able to map out probabilities in your head as you observe information, trying to predict how that information got there, and what that information might lead to. It&rsquo;s not something that can effectively be taught, but has to be practiced, refined, and revised continually. And, yes, some people are better at it than others, because we all have unique backgrounds, experiences, and environments that have shaped the way we navigate through and perceive ourselves and the world around us; but we are all capable of becoming critical thinkers. The most fun, and most difficult part, is finding out how to get there in a way that works for you.</p>
<p>So how do we develop critical thinking skills? There&rsquo;s a plethora of resources available on the internet, just Google &ldquo;How to think critically&rdquo; and get cracking. In terms of practical exercises, the best thing you can do is challenge yourself with something new, and maintain the patience in seeing it through. Learn something you know nothing about. Work on puzzles. Play games that make you think through the gameplay (like a strategy game). Take notes along the way. Journal your thoughts. Ask yourself, and others, &ldquo;why?.&rdquo; Take something apart and put it back together. Will you stumble? Probably, but the discomfort of failure is where we have the choice of giving up or learning from the failure and trying again from a different approach. If you give up, you won&rsquo;t learn, and learning is a continual process.</p>
<p><em>Why this is important for Cybersecurity:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Analyzing information requires the ability to ask questions about what the information is and how the information got there.</li>
<li>Mapping out possibilities, whether in your head or on your screen, can help lead to more solid and reasonable conclusions.</li>
<li>Having a chain of logic for others to follow to your conclusions makes you a more effective team member and leader.</li>
<li>Being able to respond to security events, hack, or troubleshoot issues, requires the ability to think through multiple avenues of approach.</li>
<li>Staying up to date with industry trends requires researching information.</li>
<li>Keeping skills up to date requires continuous learning and studying.</li>
<li>If you want to learn how to etchically hack, you need to know how to find weaknesses, which are usually hidden and have to be thought through.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2-communication">2. Communication</h2>
<p>I wasn&rsquo;t sure if I should list communication as the #1 skill or the #2 because it&rsquo;s almost equally as important as critical thinking, but regardless, you need to know how to communicate effectively with people from all walks of life who may know more or less than you do on a given topic. You need to be able to sell yourself to employers to land the job, to communicate with management and coworkers to achieve goals, write reports, and translate all of that in ways that non-technical people can also understand. Just like with critical thinking, communication isn&rsquo;t something that can be taught, but has to be learned over time, and a Google search for &ldquo;how to develop good communication skills&rdquo; can yield some fruitful results.</p>
<p>Exercises you can pursue are taking the time to write and having it read by a peer, friend, partner, etc., and using their feedback as a way to improve your writing. Focus on using proper grammar, spelling, and punctuation. Recite speeches or theatrical monologues in a mirror. Explain highly technical concepts to your friends and family in ways they can understand, using analogies to help. Avoid using AI such as ChatGPT because, as with everything else, the learning and retention comes from the challenge of discomfort and the overcoming of failure, not from having something else do the work for us.</p>
<p><em>Why this is important for Cybersecurity:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>You will need to explain what the information you&rsquo;re looking at is or may be, as well as how it got there and where it might be going.</li>
<li>Writing reports.</li>
<li>Mentoring junior analysts, as well as being able to understand senior analysts when they are mentoring you.</li>
<li>Sharing information with stakeholders and key individuals in a way that complex technical concepts can be easily understood by all present.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="3-how-computers-work">3. How Computers Work</h2>
<p>Knowing how computers work is the bare-bones basic technical foundation that you need to progress any further in Cybersecurity. While you don&rsquo;t need to have a doctorate in computer science and be designing your own chips, you should at least understand how data is stored, retrieved, and transmitted in a conceptual way, along with understanding how to navigate through various operating systems, manipulate files, perform administrative tasks, and so on. The more technical you understand a computer, the better, because every single facet of a computer can be vulnerable to an attack with the right tools, experience, and mindset; and all devices that operate with a chip of some sort are a computer and function the exact same as the device you&rsquo;re reading this from right now. You&rsquo;ll need to use a computer to perform your work, and since computers are the vessels that store the precious data, and are used to attack that data, knowing how a computer works enables you to knowing how to secure that computer, and subsequentially the data stored on it, from an attack.</p>
<p>This is a field of study in and of itself, and is so deep and broad that there&rsquo;s no feasible way to master all of it; but it&rsquo;s crucial to be able to understand how to navigate the major operating systems out there (chiefly Windows, Linux, and MacOS), how to administer the operating systems, how to manipulate files, install/uninstall programs, and on a general/conceptual level, wrap your head around the basics about how the data traverses the various components of the computer, as well as what those components are and what makes them important.</p>
<p><em>Projects to Consider:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Build your own PC</li>
<li>Upgrade a hardware module</li>
<li>Install Linux</li>
<li>Set up and install Windows and/or Linux on a Virtual Machine</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Why this is important for Cybersecurity:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Knowing how a computer works strengthens your ability to harden a computer from an attack.</li>
<li>If working as an analyst, you will need to know how to separate normal computer operation from abnormal operation.</li>
<li>Understanding how to navigate various operating systems and their unique syntaxes helps you understand activity.</li>
<li>Knowing how computers operate on a more scientific level enables understanding of how attacks can be performed in ways that may not be detected by conventional software, such as an antivirus solution.</li>
<li>Much analytical work involves understanding the overall functionality of an operating system.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="4-computer-networking">4. Computer Networking</h2>
<p>Just like with knowing how a computer works, the next step is understanding how computers talk to one-another. Networking can get heady and complex, and unfortunately our current networking functionality wasn&rsquo;t originally designed with security in mind. Knowing networking is crucial because most attacks happen from a remote attacker trying to break in to another device over the internet, and being able to make sense of the traffic and how devices on a network can be interconnected helps make you a more rounded professional.</p>
<p><em>Projects to Consider:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Set up an Ansible playbook.</li>
<li>Demo FHRP.</li>
<li>Configure a DHCP server.</li>
<li>Capture network traffic with Wireshark.</li>
<li>Deploy a WLC.</li>
<li>Set up VLANs on your home network</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Why this is important for Cybersecurity:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Knowing how devices communicate on a network is crucial for understanding most modern cyber attacks and how to defend against them.</li>
<li>Firewalls are some of the most important components in defending a network from attacks, and rely heavily on networking knowledge to configure and maintain.</li>
<li>Software and operating systems heavily utilize networking to perform critical functionality.</li>
<li>Most analytical work involves following and interpreting network traffic.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="5-system-and-network-administration">5. System and Network Administration</h2>
<p>Even though I touched on this in the past two skills, I think it&rsquo;s important to outline as a skill in itself as it&rsquo;s easy to just use a computer but it&rsquo;s another challenge to be able to manage a computer, whether remotely or interactively, and most system and network administration involves understanding how computers and networks work. I&rsquo;ve already highlighted the reasons why in the previous two, but want to rehash that knowing how to set up, configure, and maintain devices and networking infrastructure is a crucial element on your way to the Cybersecurity path because most of it involves proactively preventing problems from occurring, whether that is in setting up Active Directory accounts with appropriate permissions for users, or configuring a firewall to disallow unwanted internet traffic.</p>
<p><em>Projects to Consider:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Configure a gateway.</li>
<li>Set up a domain controller.</li>
<li>Set up an Active Directory environment.</li>
<li>Configure both Windows and Linux endpoints to connect to the domain.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="6-scripting">6. Scripting</h2>
<p>Now that you&rsquo;ve learned about computers, networks, and how to keep them running, and if you&rsquo;re pursuing projects along the way, you&rsquo;ve probably noticed there&rsquo;s a lot of functions being performed that are redundant. Scripting is an excellent way to automate the processes that you&rsquo;re trying to achieve, whether it&rsquo;s keeping patches up to date on a remote system, checking to see if devices are online, collecting information about what programs are installed or how the device is performing, and beyond. Learning scripting, whether it&rsquo;s Powershell/Batch/VisualBasic (Windows) or Bash (Linux/Unix) is another critical step to being able to make sense of a lot of attacks, as well as a great first step to learning the next skill in this list, programming.</p>
<p><em>Projects to Consider:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Too many to list.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Why this is important for Cybersecurity:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Attackers use scripts to automate attacks, and you will more than likely encounter an artifact in the form of a script. Knowing how to script enables you to be able to translate scripts other people write and determine what possible outcomes can occur from the script being run.</li>
<li>Processes and functions may need to be automated with your job. Being able to automate through scripting will save you immense time in a field where time is critical.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="7-programming">7. Programming</h2>
<p>Having a basic understanding of scripting makes programming even easier, since it ties together in a lot of ways. Pick a language and learn it. Popular programming languages in Cybersecurity include Python and C++, but ultimately any of them will suit you just fine. Malware can be written in anything, including Java, Ruby, C#, Rust, Go, and more.</p>
<p><em>Projects to Consider:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Take a scripting project you created and convert it to your programming language of choice.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Why this is important for Cybersecurity:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Knowing a programming language helps you understand how to read other peoples&rsquo; code.</li>
<li>Malware analysis becomes a lot easier by knowing how programs can be written.</li>
<li>You can create additional tools and programs to help with your research, automation, and cyber defense/offense skills.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="8-security-theory">8. Security Theory</h2>
<p>This is an element where we get a little bit off of the technical side of things. Understanding security theory is a dull, but important, step in becoming an effective Cybersecurity professional, and a lot of the concepts that are attached to the world of Cybersecurity are also security concepts that are taken from and applied in the real world. Think of something as simple as locking a door. How can you use that same concept in regards to protecting a network from a particular attack? The overall concept here is hardening, which is an element of security theory. Through this you&rsquo;ll also learn many important terms and concepts that you will be required to know in any Cybersecurity job, such as the CIA triad, AAAs of Security, what a SIEM does, or what the difference is between an IDS and IPS, and etc.</p>
<p><em>Projects to Consider:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Set up and configure a SIEM.</li>
<li>Set up and configure an IDS/IPS.</li>
<li>Write a report about a novel threat or threat actor.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Why this is important for Cybersecurity:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Learning security theory is where you will then be able to apply secure concepts to the technical aspects you&rsquo;ve learned.</li>
<li>Security theory encompasses concepts, verbiage, and terminology that are crucial to know, define, and apply in the real world and at a job.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="9-defensive-security-blue-team">9. Defensive Security (Blue Team)</h2>
<h2 id="10-offensive-security-red-team">10. Offensive Security (Red Team)</h2>
<p>Knowing how to apply security theory to computer functions, networking, scripting, and programming now makes you qualified for a job as a SOC analyst (don&rsquo;t believe me? Look for SOC Analyst jobs, and I guarantee you that the prerequesites for most of the positions currently open detail at least one skill in each of these categories). This is the first step for most in the Cybersecurity industry, and sometimes the full career for many others. By learning how to defend against attacks, if you decide to pursue offensive security (Red Team Ops), you&rsquo;ll become a more proficient penetration tester/ethical hacker by knowing how the defenses can look, and choose your approaches more carefully, which leads us to Red Team. Knowing how to defend from attacks, you can now understand how to better avoid those defences on the red team side. Additionally, #9 and #10 here are somewhat interchangeable and continual, because knowing how attacks are executed makes an analyst a more effective defender, and knowing how to defend against attacks makes for more effective attack techniques.</p>
<p>Someone who wants to focus solely on cyber defense needs to get their feet wet in the offensive side, and visa versa, because these two skills are almost interchangeable and require one-another to continually learn and grow; but the foundations in all of the preceding skills are vital in continuing that growth and knowledge.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a more in-depth understanding of how the preceding skills play in to a Cybersecurity professional&rsquo;s overall career:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Critical Thinking:</strong> Necessary to follow the attack lifecycle, understand the attacker mindset, and predicting where the next target might be or discovering where initial access occurred or could occur. Discovering and addressing security holes and vulnerabilities. Understanding motives of attackers, attribution to a specific attacker or APT, following current events both in the tech industry and in geopolitics, economics, social trends, and more to determine possible targets, threats, and techniques. Understanding human psychology and the art of war.</li>
<li><strong>Communication:</strong> Taking notes, compiling reports, and presenting these findings to relevant key personnel to be addressed. Translating these concepts to a basic level for broader understanding. Communicating security needs and why they are important. Collaboration with coworkers and vendors.</li>
<li><strong>How computers work:</strong> Finding ways where attackers can masquerade within and traverse around an operating system. Locating artifacts and Indicators of Compromise that may be hidden. Navigating through and traversing directories, user accounts, and authentication mechanisms.</li>
<li><strong>Computer Networking:</strong> Finding ways where attackers can masquerade their movement across multiple devices by masquerading their traffic in a network. Following patterns of activity and recognizing unusual or malicious network traffic, like a needle in a haystack. Recognizing network attacks as they occur.</li>
<li><strong>System Administration:</strong> Finding ways where attackers can masquerade within and traverse around an operating system. Locating artifacts and Indicators of Compromise that may be hidden. Navigating through and traversing directories, user accounts, and authentication mechanisms.</li>
<li><strong>Scripting:</strong> Automating processes. Reading and translating artifacts (i.e. malicious scripts).</li>
<li><strong>Programming:</strong> Developing programs or tools to assist with defense and automation. Malware analysis.</li>
<li><strong>Security Theory:</strong> Understanding the overall broader concepts so that when new technologies and vulnerabilities emerge they can be understood faster by applying the relevant concepts and theories to their application and use.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="bonus-specialization">Bonus: Specialization</h2>
<p>If you really want to stand out from the crowd, specialize in a particular domain or technology that requires an emphasis on security. Technologies such as Active Directory, Cisco networking products, or even a protocol such as SMB where you can become the subject matter expert (SME) for your organization. Knowing the concept or technology in and out, including how it works, how it can be attacked, and how it can be defended, makes you stand out in any interview from the broad range of candidates who know that specific something exists and what it does, but don&rsquo;t know much else.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t a one size fits all guide, but more an aggregate of information I&rsquo;ve gleaned from reading multiple writeups on navigating this field of expertise. It&rsquo;s worth repeating that Cybersecurity is not entry level, and if you haven&rsquo;t gleaned it by now, it&rsquo;s also not as glamorous or exciting as the media (and some certification and college programs) have advertised it as. It&rsquo;s a lot of tedium, a lot of logs, and a lot of learning, every single day. It requires a level of passion that is not easily found, and there are many people who pursue this career because of the belief in the glamor they&rsquo;ve been advertised but then quickly find out it&rsquo;s not what it appeared to be. It&rsquo;s overwhelming, and within the specialization of Cybersecurity are countless other specializations in various aspects. Again, it is not entry level, though you may luck out and find an employer who is willing to hire you on at an entry level role; but the learning will be up to you, and have to occur on time that you make for it. Nobody will hand you the answers, as in this field, there are rarely actual answers; just hypotheses that are backed by evidence.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t wish to discourage anyone from embarking on this career path. On the contrary, we need more skilled professionals to bridge the gap that exists, but I think it&rsquo;s important to highlight what is needed to exceed, and what is needed to grow, in order to ensure we don&rsquo;t get burned out from discovering that the reality is not the fantasy that we are led to believe.</p>
<p>Best of luck in your endeavors, and never, ever, stop learning.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>OSINT Challenge</title>
            <link>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/osint-challenge/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:50:22 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/posts/osint-challenge/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little backstory to this post: I was socializing with some of my Cybersecurity friends in an online community when one of them (who was travelling for work at the time) posted the below image, and said &amp;ldquo;OSINT challenge! Where am I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;osint_challenge_full.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get excited when these types of &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo; are presented. They pique my curiosity, and it&amp;rsquo;s also a great little exercise in critical thinking. This writeup will elaborate on my thought process from start to finish and methodology to arrive at a conclusion, but a big disclaimer here is that it&amp;rsquo;s never a one-size-fits-all solution, and anyone&amp;rsquo;s results and process will differ. My ultimate hope is that if you&amp;rsquo;re new to OSINT, or looking to get other insights, that this will help to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>A little backstory to this post: I was socializing with some of my Cybersecurity friends in an online community when one of them (who was travelling for work at the time) posted the below image, and said &ldquo;OSINT challenge! Where am I?&rdquo;</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_full.jpg" alt="osint_challenge_full.jpg"></p>
<p>I get excited when these types of &ldquo;challenges&rdquo; are presented. They pique my curiosity, and it&rsquo;s also a great little exercise in critical thinking. This writeup will elaborate on my thought process from start to finish and methodology to arrive at a conclusion, but a big disclaimer here is that it&rsquo;s never a one-size-fits-all solution, and anyone&rsquo;s results and process will differ. My ultimate hope is that if you&rsquo;re new to OSINT, or looking to get other insights, that this will help to some degree.</p>
<h2 id="step-1-start-with-the-obvious">Step 1: Start With the Obvious</h2>
<p>When investigating anything I always start by formulating questions. Things like &ldquo;Who, what how when, where, why?&rdquo; don&rsquo;t necessarily fit into a picture, but a good mindset when you&rsquo;re utterly clueless is to start broadly and then narrow it down into more granular chunks.</p>
<p>Looking at the above image, the first question I ask myself is:</p>
<p><em>What&rsquo;s most prominent in the setting?</em></p>
<p>There&rsquo;s a big clear &ldquo;Buc-ee&rsquo;s&rdquo; storefront being reflected in the passenger window of the car. The sky is big, blue, and wide open, with no trees, hills, or mountains visible on the horizon. It looks pretty dry there.</p>
<p>These are our biggest clues as to what region this is. If you&rsquo;re not from the United States, you&rsquo;d start with a Google search, possibly researching what Buc-ee&rsquo;s is and where they&rsquo;re mostly located. I already know. It&rsquo;s a prominent gas station chain in the southern USA. I&rsquo;ve sadly never been to one, but there&rsquo;s rumors they might be expanding into my state; but until then, I at least know about it from the myths and legends of my people. Either way, Google is your friend.</p>
<p>A quick visit to Google Maps yields most of the Buc-ee&rsquo;s locations in the US:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_1.png" alt="osint_challenge_1.png"></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a little surprised because I thought there were more of these locations in more states, but I&rsquo;m quickly filled with more hope from checking out the Wikipedia entry on Buc-ee&rsquo;s, confirming there aren&rsquo;t that many, with only ~50 locations in the US:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_2.png" alt="osint_challenge_2.png"></p>
<p>This is actually promising, because it allows me to start narrowing down the more likely possibilities.</p>
<h2 id="step-2-process-of-elimination">Step 2: Process of Elimination</h2>
<p>My next focus is going to be on the landscape, and Google Street View is going to be your friend here. A quick look at the street view for the locations not in Texas (Colorado, Missouri, and Kentucky) quickly show us that these aren&rsquo;t the spot, because features exist that aren&rsquo;t in the photo: Trees, mountains/hills in the distance, so this is definitely in Texas.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d repeat the process for the Texas locations, but I&rsquo;ll save you some reading time. It&rsquo;s definitely not Houston, and another hint was that the originator of this challenge was travelling for work; so the likelihood of him being out in the middle of nowheresville, TX is pretty slim. Not completely off the table, but I&rsquo;m going to eliminate those locations as possibilities unless I&rsquo;m proven wrong.</p>
<p>Honestly, you could trial and error your way through to finding this location just by using Google Street View 50 different times, but that&rsquo;s just no fun. So let&rsquo;s try narrowing it down even further.</p>
<h2 id="step-3-get-granular">Step 3: Get Granular</h2>
<p>Looking around at the picture zoomed in, I want to find some other distinguishing characteristics. A landmark, a brand, something that stands out. I see the orange/white striped roof which I recognize as a sacred shrine to the Gods of beef, aka Whataburger, and next to it, a restaurant name I&rsquo;m not familiar with: Taco Cabana (at least I think it says Cabana, it&rsquo;s a bit blurry):</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_3.png" alt="osint_challenge_3.png"></p>
<p>There&rsquo;s also what appears to be a car wash:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_4.png" alt="osint_challenge_4.png"></p>
<p>And what I&rsquo;m assuming to be across the street in the background is a strip mall, with a Hobby Lobby and Ross in there.</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_5.png" alt="osint_challenge_5.png"></p>
<p>Again, this further confirms that this individual is somewhere in Texas. The American South is the only region in the world where you can get grandma&rsquo;s yarn for her knitting projects, a discounted jacket, a gallon bucket of pecans, gas, and get your truck washed, all within a 100 yard radius. There&rsquo;s also a sign that says &ldquo;Texas&rdquo; on the object saying &ldquo;Rent Me&rdquo; in one of the above images. So definitely Texas.</p>
<p>Out of all of these establishments, Taco Cabana seems the least well-known. At least to me. Using Google Maps again, it narrows down the possibility to 3 cities: Dallas, Austin, and San Antonio.</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_6.png" alt="osint_challenge_6.png"></p>
<p>So now I can confidently say that I&rsquo;m looking for an aerial view of a Taco Cabana next door to a Whataburger, by a car wash, across the street from a Buc-ee&rsquo;s, with a strip mall across from all of it. This makes the search much, much, easier. So I decide to start with the Dallas area, and eyeball the image again to get a rough idea of how these establishments are all laid out. I redo my search for Buc-ee&rsquo;s since there aren&rsquo;t as many clustered together, and within 2 looks I finally find a hit:</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_7.png" alt="osint_challenge_7.png"></p>
<p>Google Street View of the Buc-ee&rsquo;s has almost a complete match on the location, in nearly the same spot as the original photo was taken. Jackpot!</p>
<p><img src="https://0xhyp3rion.github.io/images/osint_challenge/osint_challenge_8.png" alt="osint_challenge_8.png"></p>
<p>So our friend was at the Buc-ee&rsquo;s on 506 I-20, Terrell, TX 75160</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>This was honestly a pretty easy OSINT exercise because of all of the prominent brand names, and having a general understanding of where the brands are concentrated and what various geographical and topological features might hint towards in terms of regions and locales is a huge one-up.</p>
<p>Performing OSINT is a lot like learning how to hack. You can do it out the gate, but it becomes far easier having pre-existing knowledge and understanding of contextual information, which comes from being curious about anything and everything you look at.</p>
<p>My parents used to tell me that my endless hours of going down Wikipedia rabbit holes and perusing Google Earth was a waste of time. Well, now I can confidently say that it wasn&rsquo;t; it was just setting the foundation for a skillset that I didn&rsquo;t know I&rsquo;d be using until later on in life.</p>
<p>The most important thing to remember is that asking yourself questions are your friend. Start big, work your way down, and keep refining your process until you find a methodology that works for you.</p>
<p>Happy hunting!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
